<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-27T14:27:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">callum rhys tilbury</title><subtitle>aspiring engineer, creative, entrepreneur, leader, and friend</subtitle><author><name>callum tilbury</name><email>callum@tilbury.co.za</email></author><entry><title type="html">Starting an adventure and a blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/starting-an-adventure" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting an adventure and a blog" /><published>2021-08-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/starting-an-adventure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/starting-an-adventure">&lt;p&gt;It has finally happened! After months of planning and seemingly never-ending admin (i.e. the untold pain of being an adult), I am in beautiful Edinburgh. Right &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;, I am actually cooped up inside a hotel room, but with the city in sight and my quarantine period nearing its end, it truly feels like the adventure has begun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though starting a blog feels like a natural thing to do when embarking on such a journey, my desire to create this outlet has been brewing for quite some time. This is not because I feel my life is particularly interesting—on the contrary, my hesitation to write publicly thus far has stemmed from the feeling that it would be inconsequential, and therefore unnecessary. Moreover, writing publicly is scary. It is saying: this is me, this is my life, these are my ideas. And yet, the desire to share my thoughts, to air my ideas, has remained. Every time I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the world has social media platforms, and perhaps it is my fault for discarding that perfect opportunity. Two years ago, I deleted all of my accounts as an attempt to declutter my mind. I was, and am, philosophically opposed to these glorified advertising agencies on a macro level: their invasive methods to violate our privacy, their predatory business practices, their insatiable desire for our screen time. But my reasons extended to a personal level too: it &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; like my relationships were thriving due to the regular interactions that made my reptilian brain fizz, whereas they were in fact stagnating through passive interactions that required no real work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog and/or email newsletter approach feels like a healthy middle-ground for me: social media, in a sense, not incentivised by profit. Which means, hopefully, if you are reading what I write, it is because you care, or you are interested, or you have something meaningful to contribute. Not because I was the highest bidder for your attention, or because I used the right keywords for it to reach your homepage. Instead, I hope simply to share my adventure with the people who are interested in it. This does not limit me to people who I know personally—else I could just start a private group—for I believe sharing things publicly allows ideas to flesh out and grow. I like the idea of sharing what I do and what I see, along with the ideas that are ruminating within me. But I want to do this organically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this season, moving overseas, starting a distinctly new chapter in my life, seems to be an appropriate re-entry point to the world of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel-update&quot;&gt;Travel Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin my journey of blogging, I&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>callum tilbury</name><email>callum@tilbury.co.za</email></author><summary type="html">It has finally happened! After months of planning and seemingly never-ending admin (i.e. the untold pain of being an adult), I am in beautiful Edinburgh. Right now, I am actually cooped up inside a hotel room, but with the city in sight and my quarantine period nearing its end, it truly feels like the adventure has begun.</summary></entry></feed>